<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Lost Vaults: Magic Armors</name>
        <description>Lost Vaults: Magic Armors</description>
        <author url="https://www.reddit.com/user/MrBakudan/">u/MrBakudan</author>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="magic-armors.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/community-elements/elements-reddit/master/reddit/reddit-unearthed-arcana/lost-vaults/magic-armors.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

    <element name="Addergrease Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_ADDERGREASE">
        <description>
            <p>Forged from poisonous snake and lizard skins, this leather armor can spray venom like a cobra when its owner is attacked. While wearing this armor, you gain access to the following effects:</p>
            <p class="indent">This armor has 4 charges, and regains 1 charge at dawn. When an attack misses you, you can use a reaction to expend a charge to have the armor use the spell poison spray (Save DC 15).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="leather">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">Leather</set>
            <set name="name-format">Addergrease {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Agile Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_AGILE">
        <description>
            <p>Thanks to the materials and enchantment on this armor, this armor is considerably lighter than it normally would be as a result. While wearing this armor for purposes of AC, you can add your Dexterity modifier to your AC (Max of +4).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="medium">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_MEDIUM</set>
            <set name="name-format">Agile {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Armor of Attraction" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_ATTRACTION">
        <description>
            <p>The enchantments and material choices of this armor makes the armor extremely shiny. Eyes tend to move towards the armor, almost irresistibly so...</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, when a creature within 5 feet of you is targeted by a single target attack, you can use a reaction to make the attacker make a DC 18 Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, they must target you instead. On success, they can't be affected by the Armor of Attraction for 24 hours. You also gain anadditional 1d4 bonus to Charisma (Persuasion) checks.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="scale, breastplate, splint, or plate">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">Scale,Breastplate,Splint,Plate</set>
            <set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Attraction</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Armor of Cleansing" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_CLEANSING">
        <description>
            <p>This armor is covered in healing symbols, while the inside of the armor has many hand like runes that give the impression of the touches of clerics. While wearing this armor, whenever you regain hit points, you regain an additional 2 (including short rests). You also gain a +1d4 bonus for saving throws against poisons and diseases.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="light, medium, or heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_LIGHT|ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_MEDIUM|ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Cleansing</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Aqueous Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_AQUEOUS">
        <description>
            <p>Cold when it is touched, this armor also has the appearance of being wet, even when it is dry. The armor typically is dyed to match the colors of water, with blues and whites. This armor grants the wearer with Water breathing.</p>
            <p class="indent">The armor also has 5 charges, and regains 1 charge at dawn. Using an action, you can expend a charge and polymorph into a water elemental for 5 minutes, following the rules of the polymorph spell. You can also end the polymorph early as a bonus action.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="type" addition="light">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_LIGHT</set>
            <set name="name-format">Aqueous {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Armor of Durability" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_DURABILITY">
        <description>
            <p>This armor shows no signs of wear at anytime, giving the impression that this armor can take a hit. While wearing this armor, you gain the following effects:</p><p class="indent">This armor has 3 charges, and regains 1 charge at dawn. As a bonus action you can expend a charge and gain 5 temporary hit points, and a 1d4 bonus to Constitution saving throws. These effects last 1 minute.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Durability</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Armor of Exploits" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_EXPLOITS">
        <description>
            <p>Many arcane glyphs cover this armor, and they glow in the presence of a spell being cast, seeming to draw it energy.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once per day while wearing this armor, this armor can store a cantrip spell that is put into the armor by any willing creature. The spells save DC, attack bonus, and level are those of the caster who puts the spell into the armor. Once the spell is used, another spell can't be stored until the next dawn. After a long rest, any stored spell is also lost.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="light, medium, or heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_LIGHT|ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_MEDIUM|ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Exploits</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Armor of Negation" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_NEGATION">
        <description>
            <p>The runes of this armor seems to cover vital areas of the wearer, and can seem to move in the presence of danger. Dirt and dust never seems to stick to this armor. While wearing this armor, you gain the following effects:</p>
            <p class="indent"> Whenever you succeed on a saving throw and take half damage, you may choose to take no damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can also cast dispel magic on yourself at 4th level once per day to end a magical effect. (Bonus of +3 for higher level spells)</p>  
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="light, medium, or heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_LIGHT|ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_MEDIUM|ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Negation</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Armor of Night" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_NIGHT">
        <description>
            <p>This black set of clothes shows no reflection, even when wet. Torches seem to dim when you walk past them wearing this. While wearing this robe, you gain resistance to radiant damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">The robe has 5 charges total, and regains 1+1d4 charges at dawn. As an action, you can expend a charge to cast the spell darkness on yourself without concentration.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can also expend additional charges to increase the radius of the sphere of darkness by 5 feet each charge as a free action.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		    <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
		    <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Armor of Sacrifice" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_SACRIFICE">
        <description>
            <p>The armor depicts scenes of heroes throwing themselves in front of others to protect their allies. While wearing this armor, as a reaction you can touch a willing creature within range who is undergoing a condition that requires a saving throw to end. You transfer the condition to yourself, and you may expend a hit die to give yourself advantage on the saving throw. The Condition must require a Constitution, Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma saving throw to transfer. You may only use this feature once per day.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">{{parent}} of Sacrifice</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Armor of Starlight" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_STARLIGHT">
        <description>
            <p>These cloth set of clothes is a deep blue, with small dots of white that seem to twinkle slightly.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing these clothes, you gain resistance to radiant damage. The set also has 5 charges total, and regains 1 charge per night.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you are hit with an attack, you can use your reaction to expend a charge, causing the stars on the clothes to explode with light. The attacker must make a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or be blinded until the end of their next turn (Creature must rely on sight). You can also use a bonus action to shed dim light within 15 feet around you, and end it with a bonus action.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
		    <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
		    <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Assassinbane Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_ASSASINBANE">
        <description>
            <p>This armor depicts many circles on it, with a set of eyes moving from circle to circle.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, you ignore any disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight. You gain a +3 bonus to natural perception. Twice per day, you can also cancel a critical hit that is caused by a roll with advantage, and cause it to do normal damage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="light, medium, or heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_LIGHT|ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_MEDIUM|ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">Assassinbane {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Beastlord Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_BEASTLORD">
        <description>
            <p>Decorated with horns, teeth, and bones, this armor is made from the skins and parts of many different types of animals.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, you can cast speak with animals once per day. You also gain a +1d6 bonus to Wisdom (Animal Handling) checks made. You also have advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks made to carve or track creatures.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="leather or hide">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="armor">leather,hide</set>
            <set name="name-format">Beastlord {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Bestial Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_BESTIAL">
        <description>
            <p>This armor is crafted from skin, fur, and claws of cave bears. The enchantments of this armor allows you to draw upon their power. While wearing this armor, you gain access to the following effects:</p>
            <p class="indent">3 times per day, when you take a Dash action you can use a bonus action to make a single melee weapon attack. This melee attack gains a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="leather or hide">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">unommon</set>
            <set name="armor">leather,hide</set>
            <set name="name-format">Bestial {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Bloodiron Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_BLOODIRON">
        <description>
            <p>Armor that is treated and cooled in blood while forged, the armor has a reddish tinge to the color. While wearing this armor, you have access to the following effects:</p>
            <p class="indent">This armor has 5 charges, and regains 1 charge at dawn. With a bonus action, you can expend a charge and blood mark a target you can see. You gain an additional +2 to attack and damage rolls against the target. The mark lasts 1 minute.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">Bloodiron {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Bloodtheft Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_BLOODTHEFT">
        <description>
            <p>This armor has runes that constantly bleed, but drips no blood. The armor itself seems to always be slick with crimson.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor when you are hit with an attack, you can expend any number of hit die and regain temporary hit points equal to the amounts rolled. The creature that hit you also must make a DC 20 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, they take piercing damage equal to the amount of temporary hit points you regain, or half as much on a successful save, as blood spikes shoot out. When you bring a creature to zero hit points, you can use a bonus action to regain a single hit die.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="leather">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">legendary</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">leather</set>
            <set name="name-format">Bloodtheft {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Bolstering Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_BOLSTERING">
        <description>
            <p>Tales of this armor tell it was worn only by the greatest of leaders in all the lands. Runes on the arms on hands tell of healing powers.</p>
            <p class="armor">While wearing this armor, whenever you use hit dice during a short rest, all creatures you choose within 20 feet regain half of what you recover. You can also touch a willing creature, using an action to expend a hit dice and heal the creature by that much. Whenever you regain hit points from a spell or item, a creature of your choice within 20 feet of you regains half of what you heal.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">legendary</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">Bolstering {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Bloodfire Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_BLOODFIRE">
        <description>
            <p>Showing depictions of the Nine Hells, this armor is said to be made using Tieflings techniques.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, you gain fire resistance. This armor has 5 charges, and regains 1+1d4 charges at dawn. As a reaction, you can expend a charge to cast the spell hellish rebuke at 2nd level (save DC 15)</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="leather, scale, or plate">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">leather, scale, plate</set>
            <set name="name-format">Bloodfire {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Bonegrim Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_BONEGRIM">
        <description>
            <p>This scary looking armor is composed of a skull helmet, a ribcage breast plate, and forelimb bones for the arms and legs.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, you gain advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks, resistance to necrotic and poison damage, and no longer require food, water, and sleep.</p>
            <p class="indent">Cursed- You are unable to remove this armor as it binds to the skeleton of the wearer. It can only be removed with a remove curse spell or similar spell. If you die with this armor on, you rise as a skeleton, and attack the nearest creature. While wearing this armor, you count as an undead for terms of turn undead, vulnerabilities, and arcane senses.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="plate">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">plate</set>
            <set name="name-format">Bonegrim {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Breaching Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_BREACHING">
        <description>
            <p>This seemingly normal set of armor phases through walls slightly when touching them, seeming to give a hint to their power.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once per day while wearing this armor when you are against a wall, you can teleport to the other side without requiring line of sight. You cannot teleport if the wall is more than 10 feet thick, or if there is an obstacle in the space you would appear at (Creature or object). If there is an obstacle, you do not teleport, and the power is wasted for the day.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="light, medium, or heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_LIGHT|ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_MEDIUM|ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">Breaching {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Briarwine Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_BRIARWINE">
        <description>
            <p>An armor of Eladrin make, this armor is meant to appear as normal clothes until provoked.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, whenever you take melee damage the attacker takes 1d4 piercing damage. This armor appears to be a normal set of clothes until it is revealed with a bonus action or you are attacked. The armor returns to its other appearance after 1 minute.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">Briarwine {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Champions Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_CHAMPIONS">
        <description>
            <p>This armor appears to be slightly worn. Legends tell that the spirit of a previous hero from a forgotten era dwells inside the armor. While wearing this armor, you gain access to the following effects:</p>
            <p class="indent">This armor has 3 charges, and regains 1 charge at dawn. Whenever you are hit with an attack, as a reaction you can expend a charge and gain half the damage you have taken as temporary hit points that lasts 1 minute.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="plate or scale">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">plate,scale</set>
            <set name="name-format">Champions {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Chaos Weave Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_CHAOS_WEAVE">
        <description>
            <p>This armor has multicolor runes that seem to swirl and spin slowly all over.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, whenever you are hit with an acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder attack, as a reaction you can choose to gain resistance to that damage type until your next long rest. The elemental resistance type can only be changed up to 3 times per day.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="type" addition="light, medium, or heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_LIGHT|ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_MEDIUM|ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">Chaos Weave {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Coral Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_CORAL">
        <description>
            <p>While this armor seems heavy, when you enter water it becomes light as air. While wearing this armor, you gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed and water breathing.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="type" addition="heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">Coral {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Crystal Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_CRYSTAL">
        <description>
            <p>This armor is typically made from a clear or milky quartz and prevents negative influences on your senses and mind. While wearing this armor, you gain a 1d4 bonus to all Wisdom and Intelligence saving throws.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">Crystal {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Darkforged Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_DARKFORGED">
        <description>
            <p>Made using Duergar techniques, this dark metal armor is known for its extremely powerful resistance to force. While wearing this armor, you gain access to the following effects:</p>
            <p class="indent">This armor has 3 charges, and regains 1 at dawn. You can use a reaction to expend a charge and increase your AC by 2 for 5 rounds. (30 seconds). This effect can be stacked multiple times, however all stacked AC is lost when the first used stack expires.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" very rare="chain shirt, chain mail, scale, or plate">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">Common</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">chain shirt, chain mail, scale, plate</set>
            <set name="name-format">Darkforged {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <!-- Left the name as it is in the pdf, but should it be Deflection? -->
    <element name="Defection Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_DEFECTION">
        <description>
            <p>Dispute shows some signs of wear and tear, this deceptive looking armor is in fact extremely strong. So much so that it bounces attacks towards others. While wearing this armor, you gain access to the following effects:</p>
            <p class="indent">This armor has 5 charges, and you regain 1d4 charges at dawn. When a single target attack misses you, you can use a reaction to expend a charge, and redirect the attack within half the range of the original attack. The original attacker must reroll for a new attack against the new target, and you can expend an additional charge to give that attack advantage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">legendary</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">Defection {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>   

    <element name="Elukian Clay Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_ELUKIAN_CLAY">
        <description>
            <p>Typically deep red or pale yellow in color, this clay armor is made from enchanted clay from the elemental plane of Earth.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, you gain resistance to acid damage, and a +1d6 bonus to all Constitution saving throws. Once per day, you can also gain immunity to acid damage for 1 round (6 seconds) as a free action.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="scale or plate">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="armor">scale, plate</set>
            <set name="name-format">Elukian Clay {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Faymind Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_FAYMIND">
        <description>
            <p>Using enchanted silver from the Faewild, this armor set has dancing lights around it that can be used defensively. While wearing this armor, 5 motes of light surround you. You can have the lights around you provide torch light with a bonus action. You can also send one out to hover within 30 feet of you. If you leave further than 60 feet of a mote, the mote of light returns to you.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once per day, you can use a reaction to burn the motes of light against a creature that targets you for an attack. The creature must make a DC 16 Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, they are stunned until the end of their next turn. The motes are destroyed when this is done, and return by the next dawn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="light">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_LIGHT</set>
            <set name="name-format">Faymind {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Flickersight Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_FLICKERSIGHT">
        <description>
            <p>Enchanted with Shadowfell magic, this armor is a darker color with pitch black runes. While wearing this armor, you gain minor dark vision, which makes dim light appear as bright light within 15 feet, and darkness appear as dim light. Once per day you can cause your body to become semitransparent, gaining advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks. This effect lasts 5 rounds (30 seconds)</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="light">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_LIGHT</set>
            <set name="name-format">Flickersight {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Fortification Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_FORTIFICATION">
        <description>
            <p>This armor is forged using typical Dragonborn methods, and as such is well suited for combat. While wearing this armor, whenever you are hit with a critical hit, roll a d20. If you roll a 16-20, the critical attack becomes a normal hit.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="scale or plate">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">scale, plate</set>
            <set name="name-format">Fortification {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Frostburn Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_FROSTBURN">
        <description>
            <p>On the outside, this set of plate mail gathers a fine layer of frost. However, those who wear it will attest to the warmth that it provides.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, you gain resistance to extreme heat and cold environments. You also gain resistance to cold and fire damage. This armor has 5 charges, and regains 1d4 charges at dawn. When a friendly creature within 10 feet is attacked, you can use your reaction to expend a charge and grant that creature resistance to either fire or cold damage until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="plate">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">plate</set>
            <set name="name-format">Frostburn {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Frozen Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_FROZEN">
        <description>
            <p>Motes of ice float around this armor made of ice, enchanted never to melt. Despite its appearance, it keeps the wearer warm.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, you gain resistance to extreme cold environments. You also gain resistance to cold damage. Once per day, you can add 1d6 cold damage to a melee or ranged attack.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="scale or plate">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">scale, plate</set>
            <set name="name-format">Frozen {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Giantdodger Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_GIANTDODGER">
        <description>
            <p>This very simple looking set of leather armor is very common among the halfling heroes of the world, mostly in part due to the stories and legends that surround it.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, when a creature with a size category larger than yours misses with an attack, you can use a reaction to move 1/2 your walking speed without opportunity attacks. You also gain advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks against that creature until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="leather">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="armor">leather</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="name-format">Giantdodger {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Heartening Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_HEARTENING">
        <description>
            <p>The glyphs on this armor not only give you courage to face your fears, but to come back at them as well.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, you gain a +1d4 on Wisdom saving throws against fear effects. When you are successful on a save against a fear effect, you also gain temporary hit points equal to your level.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type" addition="scale or plate">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">scale, plate</set>
            <set name="name-format">Heartening {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Illithid Robes" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_ILLITHID_ROBES">
        <description>
            <p>A very tight and slick set of robes, these robes are common amongst the mind flayer race. The enchantments upon them show the willingness to use thralls as shields.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this robe, you gain resistance to psychic damage. 3 times per day when you take damage from an attack, you can choose a willing creature in sight, and split the damage in half with that creature as a reaction.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp" override="false">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="rarity">very rare</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Immunizing Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_IMMUNIZING">
        <description>
            <p>This armor is sleek and white, giving a sense of purity. The runes on the armor glow in the presence of poison and disease.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, you gain resistance to poison damage. You also make saving throws against poisons and diseases with advantage.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type" addition="scale or plate">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="armor">scale, plate</set>
            <set name="name-format">Immunizing {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Imposters Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_IMPOSTERS">
        <description>
            <p>A plain looking set of metal armor, with a quick command word you can transform this armor into a robe or set of clothes.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, you can use a bonus action to transform your armor from its current state into a set of common clothes or back. You lose the AC armor bonus while in common clothes form. You also gain advantage on Charisma (Deception) checks to convince others of yours clothes being normal.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type" addition="heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">Imposters {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Irrefutable Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_IRREFUTABLE">
        <description>
            <p>A simple but imposing set of armor, useful for making creatures bow before you.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once per day while wearing this armor, you can force a creature you can see to roll with disadvantage against a single Wisdom check or saving throw. The creature must rely on sight to be affected. You also gain a +1d4 bonus to Charisma (Intimidation) checks.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type" addition="light, medium, or heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_LIGHT|ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_MEDIUM|ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">Irrefutable {{parent}}</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Laughing Death Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_LAUGHING_DEATH">
        <description>
            <p>This armor has many sinister looking ornaments on it. A faint cackling can be heard when the armor is stuck.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, you gain resistance to necrotic damage. This armor has 3 charges, and regains 1 charge at dawn. When you are hit with a melee attack, use your reaction to expend a charge to cast inflict wounds, using your Dexterity modifier for the attack roll.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type" addition="light">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_LIGHT</set>
            <set name="name-format">Laughing Death {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Lifegiving Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_LIFEGIVING">
        <description>
            <p>This armor is covered in runes and glyphs of protection and healing.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, you gain resistance to necrotic damage. Once per day while wearing this armor you can expend a bonus action to roll a hit die and regain health.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type" addition="plate">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="armor">plate</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="name-format">Lifegiving {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Loom Weave Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_LOOM_WEAVE">
        <description>
            <p>Made with an unusual technique of weaving soil into the cloth, it gives the clothes the abilities to wield earthen powers. While wearing these clothes, you gain access to the following effects:</p>
            <p class="indent">These clothes have 2 charges, and regains 1 charge at dawn. You can use an action to expend a charge to cast Maximilian’s earthen grasp (Save DC 15).</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Martyr's Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_MARTYRS">
        <description>
            <p>A crimson tinted armor with transmutation glyphs that can help protect allies.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, as a bonus action you can touch a willing creature, and suffer a -1 penalty to AC to increase the creature’s AC by +1 until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type" addition="scale or plate">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">scale, plate</set>
            <set name="name-format">Martyr's {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Meliorating Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_MELIORATING">
        <description>
            <p>A dull steel armor that displays a simple, but well made design. While wearing this armor, when you take damage you can use a reaction to increase your AC by +1 until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type" addition="heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">Meliorating {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Mirrorsheen Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_MIRRORSHEEN">
        <description>
            <p>Made with magically enchanted metallic threads, the metallic sheen of this armor is highly reflective.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this armor, you gain resistance to radiant damage. Once per day when you are the target of a ranged single target attack you can change the target of that attack to another creature within 5 feet of you as a reaction. If you are hit with a radiant damage attack, all creatures within 5 feet of you must make a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, they are blinded until the end of their next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type" addition="light">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">rare</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_LIGHT</set>
            <set name="name-format">Mirrorsheen {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Pelaurum Armor" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_PELAURUM">
        <description>
            <p>A golden sheen on this set of armor reminds the wearer of the might of the sun god. You gain resistance to fire and radiant damage while wearing this armor.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="type" addition="heavy">Armor</set>
            <set name="rarity">uncommon</set>
            <set name="attunement">true</set>
            <set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
            <set name="name-format">Pelaurum {{parent}}</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

    <element name="Prismatic Robe" type="Magic Item" source="The Lost Vaults" id="ID_RDDT_LV_MAGIC_ITEM_PRISMATIC_ROBE">
        <description>
            <p>A rainbow colored robe that appears in dull colors at first before springing to life when used.</p>
            <p class="indent">While wearing this robe, when you are hit with an attack of the following elemental types, you gain resistance to the elemental type at the end of your turn. The elemental types are fire, cold, poison, lightning, or acid. This armor has 6 charges, and regains 1 charge at dawn. You can an action to expend a number of charges to cast the following spells:</p>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Charge Cost</td><td>Spell</td><td>Save</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>2</td><td>prismatic spray</td><td>DC 20</td></tr>
                <tr><td>6</td><td>prismatic wall</td><td>DC 20</td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
            <set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
            <set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
            <set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
            <set name="rarity">Common</set>
        </setters>
    </element>

</elements>