<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>The Nebula Otherworldly Patron</name>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="warlock-the-nebula.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/community-elements/elements-reddit/master/reddit/reddit-unearthed-arcana/all-the-lights-in-the-sky-are-stars/warlock-the-nebula.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="The Nebula" type="Archetype" source="All the Lights in the Sky are Stars" id="ID_AEYANA_ATLAS_ARCHETYPE_WARLOCK_THE_NEBULA">
        <supports>Otherworldly Patron</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your patron is a cloud of interstellar gas, chaotic and raw. You have bound yourself to this primeval being, allowing you to bear the power of creation that is the nebula’s nature.</p>
            <p class="indent">The nebula is a chaotic force of creation, and its desire to spawn new things into being are imparted upon its warlocks.</p>
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_ATLAS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_NEBULA_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_ATLAS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_NEBULA_SHIMMERING_CLOUD" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_ATLAS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_NEBULA_STARDUST_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_ATLAS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_NEBULA_GASEOUS_EVASION" />
            <div element="ID_AEYANA_ATLAS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_NEBULA_STAR_FORMATION" />
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_ATLAS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_NEBULA_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_ATLAS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_NEBULA_SHIMMERING_CLOUD" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_ATLAS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_NEBULA_STARDUST_MAGIC" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_ATLAS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_NEBULA_GASEOUS_EVASION" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_AEYANA_ATLAS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_NEBULA_STAR_FORMATION" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Expanded Spell List" type="Archetype Feature" source="All the Lights in the Sky are Stars" id="ID_AEYANA_ATLAS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_NEBULA_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
        <description>
            <p>The Nebula lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</p>
            <h5>NEBULA EXPANDED SPELLS</h5>
            <table>
                <thead>
                    <tr><td>Warlock Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td><i>absorb elements<sup>XGtE</sup>, chromatic orb</i></td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><i>dragon’s breath<sup>XGtE</sup>, dust devil<sup>XGtE</sup></i></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><i>elemental weapon, protection from energy</i></td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td><i>conjure minor elementals, fabricate</i></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><i>conjure elemental, creation</i></td></tr>
            </table>
            <h5>VARIANT: ALTERNATIVE SPELLS</h5>
            <p>For players who do not have access to <i>Xanathar’s Guide to Everything</i>, the spells in the Expanded Spell List <i>absorb elements</i>, <i>dragon’s breath</i>, and <i>dust devil</i> can be replaced with <i>color spray</i>, <i>continual flame</i>, and <i>flaming sphere</i> respectively.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <spellcasting name="Warlock" extend="true">
            <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_ABSORB_ELEMENTS</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CHROMATIC_ORB</extend>
            <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_DRAGONS_BREATH</extend>
            <extend>ID_XGTE_SPELL_DUST_DEVIL</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_WEAPON</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_MINOR_ELEMENTALS</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FABRICATE</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CONJURE_ELEMENTAL</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATION</extend>
        </spellcasting>
    </element>
    <element name="Shimmering Cloud" type="Archetype Feature" source="All the Lights in the Sky are Stars" id="ID_AEYANA_ATLAS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_NEBULA_SHIMMERING_CLOUD">
        <description>
            <p>At 1st level, the powers of the nebula come to your protection. When you cast a spell using a warlock spell slot, you can create a cloud of glowing stardust around you. The cloud sheds dim light in a 10-foot radius. The cloud has hit points equal to 5 times the level of the warlock spell slot expended. Whenever you take damage, the cloud shifts to protect you, taking the damage instead. The cloud lingers until it is reduced to 0 hit points, or until you take a short or long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you cast another spell using a warlock spell slot while the cloud has more than 0 hit points, the cloud’s hit points become equal to 5 times the level of the warlock spell slot expended.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you cast a spell using a warlock spell slot, you can create a cloud of glowing stardust around you. The cloud sheds dim light in a 10-foot radius. The cloud has hit points equal to 5 times the level of the warlock spell slot expended. Whenever you take damage, the cloud shifts to protect you, taking the damage instead. The cloud lingers until it is reduced to 0 hit points, or until you take a short or long rest. If you cast another spell using a warlock spell slot while the cloud has more than 0 hit points, the cloud’s hit points become equal to 5 times the level of the warlock spell slot expended.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Stardust Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="All the Lights in the Sky are Stars" id="ID_AEYANA_ATLAS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_NEBULA_STARDUST_MAGIC">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, you gain the ability to bring objects into creation using stardust. You can expend hit points from your shimmering cloud to cast a warlock spell you know at its lowest level without expending a spell slot. The number of hit points expended equals 10 times the spell’s level.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, while your Shimmering Cloud has more than 0 hit points, you can expend 1 hit point from the cloud as a bonus action to coalesce stardust and create an inanimate object in your hand or on the ground in an unoccupied space within the cloud. This object can be no larger than 3 feet on a side and weigh no more than 10 pounds, and its form must be that of a nonmagical object that you have seen. The object is visibly magical, radiating dim light out to 5 feet, and vanishes after 1 hour.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can expend hit points from your Shimmering Cloud to cast a warlock spell you know at its lowest level without expending a spell slot. The number of hit points expended equals 10 times the spell’s level. Additionally, while your Shimmering Cloud has more than 0 hit points, you can expend 1 hit point from the cloud as a bonus action to coalesce stardust and create an inanimate object in your hand or on the ground in an unoccupied space within the cloud. This object can be no larger than 3 feet on a side and weigh no more than 10 pounds, and its form must be that of a nonmagical object that you have seen. The object is visibly magical, radiating dim light out to 5 feet, and vanishes after 1 hour.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Gaseous Evasion" type="Archetype Feature" source="All the Lights in the Sky are Stars" id="ID_AEYANA_ATLAS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_NEBULA_GASEOUS_EVASION">
        <description>
            <p>At 10th level, you learn to dissipate and reform your body in order to avoid harm. When you are hit with an attack from an attacker you can see, you can use your reaction to become amorphous gas and negate the damage. Until the start of your next turn, you remain as gas and have resistance to all damage.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction" usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>When you are hit with an attack from an attacker you can see, you can become amorphous gas and negate the damage. Until the start of your next turn, you remain as gas and have resistance to all damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Star Formation" type="Archetype Feature" source="All the Lights in the Sky are Stars" id="ID_AEYANA_ATLAS_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THE_NEBULA_STAR_FORMATION">
        <description>
            <p>At 14th level, you learn to materialize your patron’s powers in the creation of a new star. Choose a point within 60 feet you can see. A miniature star bursts into existence at the chosen point. Each creature within 30 feet of the star when it first appears must make a Constitution saving throw against your warlock spell save DC. On a failed save, a creature takes 6d10 radiant damage and is blinded for 1 minute. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and isn’t blinded. At the end of each of its turns, the target can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on a success.</p>
            <p class="indent">The star shines for one minute, and provides bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. Creatures within 30 feet of the star have disadvantage on saving throws against your warlock spells.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>Choose a point within 60 feet you can see. A miniature star bursts into existence at the chosen point. Each creature within 30 feet of the star when it first appears must make a Constitution saving throw (save DC {{spellcasting:dc:cha}}). On a failed save, a creature takes 6d10 radiant damage and is blinded for 1 minute. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and isn’t blinded. At the end of each of its turns, the target can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on a success. The star shines for one minute, and provides bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. Creatures within 30 feet of the star have disadvantage on saving throws against your warlock spells.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    
</elements>